Preliminary Inventory of the Tadeusz Kusnierz Collection, 1938-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
Tadeusz Kusnierz Collection,
1938-1946
47010
Kusnierz, Tadeusz
9 manuscript boxes (3.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Government documents, statutes, charts, historical studies, statistical data, clippings, military orders, and photographs, relating to conditions in Poland during World War II; Polish politics and government, and activities of the Germans in Poland during the German occupation; and the internal structure, public administration, and general activities of the Polish Government-in-Exile. Photocopy.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Sikorski, Wladyslaw, 1881-1943.; Poland. Ministerstwo Odbudowy.; Poland. Ministerstwo Sprawiedliwosci.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.
Container List
- Bezpieczenstwo w Polsce w swietle nowych przepisow karnych, wprowadzonych w zycie przez Rzad Tymczasowy w Warsz., (1 copy) (Box 1)
- Dziennik Ustaw Rzeczypospolitej Polskiej.
  - year 1939. No. 100-106.
  - year 1940. No. 1-16.
  - year 1941. No. 1,5,6,7.
  - year 1942. No. 1,2,4-11.
  - year 1943. No. 1-10.
  - year 1944. No. 1-15.
  - year 1945. No. 1-11.
- Skorowidz Dziennika Ustaw., (3 vol., 1 pamphlet)
- Historia Prawa Koscielnego., (1 copy)
- Historia Prawa Koscielnego - prawo karne i majatkowe., (1 copy)
- Historia Prawa Koscielnego - stosounek Kosciola do Panstwa., (1 copy) (Box 2)
- Kodeks Cywilny Krolestwa Polskiego /Prawo osobowe z 1825 roku/, (1 copy)
- Kodeks Cywilny Napoleona /Ksiega II-ga, prawo rzeczowe/, (1 copy)
- Kodeks Cywilny Napoleona /Ksiega III-cia, prawo spadkowe/, (1 copy)
- Kodeks Handlowy, 1943., (1 copy)
- Kodeks Karny, 1944., (1 copy)
- Kodeks Zobowiazan, 1942., (1 copy)
- Konstytucja 3-go Maja itd., (1 copy)
- Narodowosciowe i Gospodarcze Problemy Pogranioza Polsko-Niemieckiego., (1 copy)
- Niemiecka Ordynacja Gminna z 30.1.1935., (1 copy)
- Niemiecka Ustawa Postepowania Cywilnego /Ksiagi 3-7./, 1945., (1 copy)
- Nauka o Panstwie, 1942 Dr. Edward Muszalski., (1 copy)
- Nauka o Panstwie Oz.II. Dr. Edward Muszalski, 1944., (1 copy)
- Niemiecka Ustawa Postepowania Gywilnego /Ks. i i II./, 1945., (1 copy)
- Organizacja Administracji Publicznej Rzeszy i Prus., 1944, (1 copy)
- Polskie Ordynacje Wyborcze, 1943., (1 copy)
- Polskie Prawo Kartelowe, 1942., (1 copy)
- Prawa i Zwyczaje Wojny Ladowej, 1944., (1 copy)
- Prawo Administracyjne, 1942. Wl. Czapinski., (1 copy) (Box 3)
- Prawo Hypoteczne z roku 1818 oraz Prawo o Przywilejach i Hypotecznych z roku 1825., (1 copy)
- Prawo o Malzenstwie z roku 1836., (1 copy)
- Prawo o Ustroju Adwokatury, 1943., (1 copy)
- Prawo Pracy, 1942., (1 copy)
- Prawo Przemyslowe Mng. J. Kasztelewicz 1944., (1 copy)
- Prawo [UNK] we Wspolczesnej Anglji Michal Smigielski, 1942., (1 copy)
- Projekty Ordynacji Wyborczych do Sejmu i Senatu Edward Dubanowicz, 1943., (1 copy)
- Projekt Ustawy o Naczelnej lzbie Gospodarczej i Uzasadnienie Edward Dubanowicz., (1 copy)
- Pruski Samorzad Powiatowy Dr.Andrzej Cichowski., (1 copy)
- Przeglad Ustaw i Rozporzadzen Dotyezacych Wymiaru Sprawiedliwosci w latach 1918-1939. Sedzia Roman Haiman., (1 copy)
- Rozporzadzenie o Kasowosci i Rachunkowosci Gminnej Rzeszy Niem eckiej z dn.2.XI.38., (1 copy)
- Rozporzadzenie o Przedsiebiorstwach Wlasnych Rzeszy Niem. z dn.21.XIa38., (1 copy)
- Rozporzdsenie o Sporzadzaniu i Wykonaniu Budzetu Gmin Rzeszy Niem. z dn.4.XI.37., (1 copy)
- Sadownictwo Karne Prof. Stefan Glaser., (1 copy)
- Teorja Prawa Cz.I. Prof.dr.Eugeniusz Jarra., (1 copy)
- Teorja Prawa Cz.II. Prof.dr.Eugeniusz Jarra., (1 copy)
- Zarys Polskiego Kodeksu Postepowania Cywilnego Dr.Bernard Ziffer., (1 copy)
- Various material
  - Organizacja Administracji Publicznej - Julian Suski., (1 copy)
  - Organizacja Urzedow Centralnych /tables/, (1 copy)
  - Partia Narodowo-Socjalistyczna Rzeszy Niemieckiej:
    - Tom 1. Prusy Wschodnie 1 Obszar Gdanska., (1 copy)
    - Tom 2. Pomorze Zachodnie., (1 copy)
    - Tom 3. Rejencja Slubicka 1 Dolne Luzyce., (1 copy) (Box 4)
    - Tom 4. Slask i Powiaty Górnoluzyckie., (1 copy)
  - Panstwowa Sluzba Cywilna - Jan Kosciolek., (1 copy)
  - Wymiar Sprawiedliwosci w Odrodzonej Polsce 22.VII.44. - 22.VII.45. /published by Provisional Warsaw Government/, (1 copy)
- Material on German war crimes against the Polish nation
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Box 4, Othertype No. 1)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 2)
  - An die Bevolkerung von Warschau - Do ludnosci m.warszawy., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 3)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 4)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 5)
  - Aufruf - Odezwa., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 6)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 7)
  - 1000 RM - Belohnung, Nagrody., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 8)
  - Rundschreiben., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 9)
  - Rozporzadzenie /sprawa igo Syma/, (1 copy) (Othertype No. 10)
  - Jak zginal igo Sym /Nowy Kurjer Warsz./, (2 copies) (Othertype No. 11)
  - Odezwa dr.Franka do ludnosci Gub.Gen., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 12)
  - Widok Warszawy podany przez prase niemiecka jako widok Londynu., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 13)
  - Pismo rzadu Gen. Gub. w sprawie ewakuacji Polaków i Zydów z terenów zachodnich., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 14)
  - Przeglad prasy niemieckiej z lipca 1941., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 15)
  - Die Ausschaltung des Polentums., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 16)
  - The Germans rob Polish libraries., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 17)
  - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 18)
  - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 19)
  - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 20)
  - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 21)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 22)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 23)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 24)
  - Bekanntmachung., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 25)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 26)
  - Nagroda 5 milonów zl. /napad na transport/., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 27)
  - An die Bevolkerung Warschan - Do ludnosci miasta warszawy., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 28)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 29)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 30)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 31)
  - Bekanntmachung., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 32)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 33)
  - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 34)
  - Bekanntmachung., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 35)
  - Zolnierzom nekrolog rozlepiony w warszawie przez Armje Krajowa/., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 36)
  - Bekanntmachung - Ogloszenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 37)
  - Swiadectwo wykonania obowiazku kontry-bucyjnego / Zl.5./., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 38)
  - Swiadestwo wykonania obowiazku kontry-bucyjnego / Zl. 30./., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 39)
  - Bekanntmachung - Obwieszczenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 40)
  - Egzekucja przez powieszenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 41)
  - Egzekucja przez powieszenie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 42)
  - Egzekucja uliczna w Warszawie., (1 copy) (Othertype No. 43)
- Material on German war crimes against the Polish nation / sentences of death/
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 11.II.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 110)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 6.v.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 111)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 17.v.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 112)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, VI.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 113)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 18.VI.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 114)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 23.VII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 115)
  - Danziger Vorposten, 27.VII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 116)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 30.VII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 117)
  - Danziger Neuste Nachrichten, 16.VII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 118)
  - Kattowitzer Zeitung, 5.VII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 119)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 5.VII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 120)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 27.VIII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 121)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 2.VIII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 122)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 4.VIII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 123)
  - Danziger Vorposten, 23.IX.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 124)
  - Danziger Neuste Nachrichten, 16.IX.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 125)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 16.IX.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 126)
  - Münchner Neuste Nachrichten, 1.X.42., (2 copies) (Box 5, Othertype No. 127)
  - Danziger Stadtrundschau, 17.X.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 128)
  - Danziger Vorposten, 29.XI.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 129)
  - Bromberger Stadtrundschau, 12.XI.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 130)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 10.XI.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 131)
  - Danziger Vorpostem, 21.XI.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 132)
  - Danziger Neuste Nachrichten, 20.XI.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 133)
- Material on German war crimes against the Polish nation
  - Breslauer Neueste Nachrichten, 19.XII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 134)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 2.XII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 135)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 12.XII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 136)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 8.XII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 137)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 3.XII.42., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 138)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 14.I.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 139)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 20.I.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 140)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 23.I.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 141)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter 3.II.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 142)
  - Oberschlesische Zeitung, 13.II.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 143)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 23.II.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 144)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 1.III.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 145)
  - Oberschlesische Zeitung, 5.III.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 146)
  - Ostdeutscher Seobachter, 9.IV.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 147)
  - Danziger Neuste Nachrichten, 16.IV.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 148)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 21.V.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 149)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 5.VI.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 150)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 7.VI.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 151)
  - Litzmannstädter Zeitung, 8.VI.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 152)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 16.VI.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 153)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 19.VI.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 154)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 28.VI.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 155)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 6.VII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 156)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 24.VII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 157)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 27.VII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 158)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 1.VIII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 159)
  - Oberschlesische Zeitung, 8.VIII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 160)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 9.VIII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 161)
  - Danziger Vorposten, 30.VIII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 162)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 9.IX.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 163)
  - Ostdeutscher Beobachter, 20.IX.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 164)
  - Litzmannstäster Zeitung, 20.X.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 165)
  - Litzmannstäster Zeitung, 18.XII.43., (2 copies) (Othertype No. 166)
- Likwidacja ghetta warszawskiego /pamphlet/ (not located)., (1 copy) (Box 5)
- Administracja okupacyjns w Gen.Gubernatorstwie /book/, (1 copy)
- Poland accuses /German war criminals/ /pamphlet/, (2 copies)
- The German new order in Poland /Polish black book/ (not located)., (1 copy)
- 30 volumes of lists of names of victims dead in German concentration camps /taken from original official German records, lack of some volumes is brought about by the fact that they can not be obtain in Germany/.
- vol.B4, B5, C1, C2, D1
- D2, E1, O., P1, P2, P3, PQ, R1 (Box 6)
- R2, R3, S1, S2, S3, S4, S5, Schl (Box 7)
- Sch2, ST, T1, T2, UV (Box 8)
- W1, W2, W3, YZ (Box 9)